42 Waterbridge Lane, Markham, ON, L3R 8V9, Canada

८ (+1) 647-563-4492
 | ■ earlchow2000@gmail.com
 | ■ e23chow@uwaterloo.ca
 | ● 4B Geomatics

Summary_

Current 4B Geomatics student with over 1 year of experience working with GIS, Python, Excel VBA, data visualization, and data analysis. Proven proficiency in ArcGIS, Python, ArcPy, Excel, PowerBI, VBA, SQL, and general technical knowledge.

Work Experience

Region of Peel, Health Intelligence & Analytics

Mississauga, ON

COORDINATOR, HEALTH ANALYTICS

May. 2022 - Present

- Lead division-wide training sessions on ArcGIS Online usage and basic web map creation
- Onboarded new co-op students on ArcGIS, current projects, and department data standards

Analyst, Data & GIS Jan. 2022 - Apr. 2022

- · Worked with senior team members to develop, and implement a standardized GIS metadata format
- Collaborated with GIS teams to design multiple map templates in ArcMap
- Automated spatial analysis processes using a combination of Python, ArcPy, and Excel
- Produced multiple PowerBI dashboards and data visualizations from a variety of data sources
- · Identified ideal COVID vaccination locations using a variety of existing data and spatial analysis techniques

Analyst, Data & GIS May 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Created and maintained an ArcGIS Online web map of COVID planning data
- Automated feature layer calculations and update processes using Python and ArcPy, reducing update times by over 90%
- Developed reconciliation tools used to validate COVID vaccination data by vaccination clinics using Excel and VBA
- Performed statistical analysis on vaccination clinic efficiency rates using Python and Excel

Metrolinx North York, ON

Bus Operations Planner Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2020

- · Developed bus scheduling applications using Python to schedule internal bus movements, reducing planning time by over 80%
- · Worked with senior team members to finalize and implement planned Bus schedules into testing databases
- · Produced accurate daily cost estimates of toll road usage from bus routes in ArcMap using spatial analysis techniques
- Developed Excel templates to calculate bus route costs using pivot tables and VBA

Projects

GTA Hospital Suitability Analysis

https://chowe123.github.io/EarlChow/Hospital_Analysis.pdf

Dec. 2021

- · Identified ideal hospital locations in the Greater Toronto Area based upon variables and weightings through literature review
- Performed using network and raster analysis in ArcMap

Geodatabase Updater GUI

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/CHOWE123/GDB-UPDATE-GUI

Jan. 2021

- Developed an GUI application which updates a geodatabase from an Excel file
- · Application allows users to maintain and update GIS data without knowledge of ArcGIS or other GIS software
- Coded using Python, ArcPy, and Tkinter

Education

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, ON

CANDIDATE FOR BACHELOR OF ENVIRONMENTAL STUDIES, HONOURS GEOMATICS

Sept. 2018 - Present

• 4th Year Honours Geomatics, Minor in Computing

Technical Skills

Programming: Python, ArcPy, Excel VBA, Javascript, SQL, R, C

GIS Software: ArcGIS Pro, ArcGIS, ArcGIS Online, QGIS, PostgreSQL, Google Earth Engine

Other Software: Excel, PowerBI, Adobe Creative Suite